let questions = [
    {
        question: 'Which type of sentence expresses strong emotions or excitement?',
        choices: ['Declararative', 'Interrogative', 'Exclamatory', 'Imperative'],
        correctAnswer: 'c',
        word: 'Exclamatory',
        definition: 'An exclamatory sentence expresses strong emotions or excitement. Example: What a beautiful sunset!'
    },
    {
        question: 'Which sentence is an example of an imperative sentence?',
        choices: ['What time is it?', 'Please pass the salt.', 'I like ice cream', 'I like that dress.'],
        correctAnswer: 'b',
        word: 'Please pass the salt.',
        definition: 'An imperative sentence gives a command or makes a request. Example: Please pass the salt.'
    },
    {
        question: 'She is a talented singer.',
        choices: ['Declarative', 'Interrogative', 'Exclamatory', 'Imperative'],
        correctAnswer: 'a',
        word: 'declarative',
        definition: 'A declarative sentence makes a statement or provides information. Example: She is a talented singer.'
    },
    {
        question: 'Please pass the salt.',
        choices: ['Declarative', 'Interrogative', 'Imperative', 'Exclamatory'],
        correctAnswer: 'c',
        word: 'Imperative',
        definition: ' An imperative sentence gives a command or makes a request.'
    },
    {
        question: 'What time does the movie start?',
        choices: ['Declarative', 'Interrogative', 'Imperative', 'Exclamatory'],
        correctAnswer: 'b',
        word: 'Interrogative',
        definition: 'An interrogative sentence asks a question.'
    },
    {
        question: 'The sun is shining brightly today.',
        choices: ['Declarative', 'Interrogative', 'Imperative', 'Exclamatory'],
        correctAnswer: 'a',
        word: 'Declarative',
        definition: 'declarative sentence makes a statement or expresses an idea.'
    },
    {
        question: 'Don\'t forget to water the plants.',
        choices: ['Declarative', 'Interrogative', 'Imperative', 'Exclamatory'],
        correctAnswer: 'c',
        word: 'Imperative',
        definition: 'An imperative sentence gives a command or makes a request.'
    },
    {
        question: 'What a beautiful sunset!',
        choices: ['Declarative', 'Interrogative', 'Imperative', 'Exclamatory'],
        correctAnswer: 'd',
        word: ' Exclamatory',
        definition: 'An exclamatory sentence expresses strong emotion or excitement.'
    },
    {
        question: 'Take out the trash before you leave.',
        choices: ['Declarative', 'Interrogative', 'Imperative', 'Exclamatory'],
        correctAnswer: 'c',
        word: ' Imperative',
        definition: 'An imperative sentence gives a command or makes a request.'
    },
    {
        question: 'I love reading books.',
        choices: ['Declarative', 'Interrogative', 'Imperative', 'Exclamatory'],
        correctAnswer: 'a',
        word: 'Declarative',
        definition: ' A declarative sentence makes a statement or expresses an idea. '
    },
    {
        question: 'Are you coming to the party?',
        choices: ['Declarative', 'Interrogative', 'Imperative', 'Exclamatory'],
        correctAnswer: 'b',
        word: 'Interrogative',
        definition: 'An interrogative sentence asks a question.'
    },
    {
        question: 'She ran the marathon in record time!',
        choices: ['Declarative', 'Interrogative', 'Imperative', 'Exclamatory'],
        correctAnswer: 'd',
        word: 'Exclamatory',
        definition: 'An exclamatory sentence expresses strong emotion or excitement.'
    },
    {
        question: 'Please turn off the lights before you go to bed.',
        choices: ['Declarative', 'Interrogative', 'Imperative', 'Exclamatory'],
        correctAnswer: 'c',
        word: 'Imperative',
        definition: 'An imperative sentence gives a command or makes a request.'
    },
    {
        question: 'Close the door',
        choices: ['Declarative', 'Interrogative', 'Imperative', 'Exclamatory'],
        correctAnswer: 'c',
        word: 'Imperative',
        definition: 'An imperative sentence gives a command or makes a request.'
    },
    {
        question: 'he sun is shining brightly.',
        choices: ['Declarative', 'Interrogative', 'Imperative', 'Exclamatory'],
        correctAnswer: 'a',
        word: 'Declarative',
        definition: 'declarative sentence makes a statement or expresses an idea.'
    },
    {
        question: 'What a beautiful day!',
        choices: ['Declarative', 'Interrogative', 'Imperative', 'Exclamatory'],
        correctAnswer: 'd',
        word: 'Exclamatory',
        definition: 'An exclamatory sentence expresses strong emotions or excitement. Example: What a beautiful sunset!'
    },
    {
        question: 'what type of sentences makes a statement of provide information?',
        choices: ['Declarative', 'Interrogative', 'Imperative', 'Exclamatory'],
        correctAnswer: 'a',
        word: 'Declarative',
        definition: 'declarative sentence makes a statement or expresses an idea.'
    },
    {
        question: 'Which type of sentence is used to ask a question?',
        choices: ['Declarative', 'Interrogative', 'Imperative', 'Exclamatory'],
        correctAnswer: 'b',
        word: 'Interrogative',
        definition: 'An interrogative sentence asks a question.'
    },
    {
        question: 'What type of sentence gives a command or makes a request?',
        choices: ['Declarative', 'Interrogative', 'Imperative', 'Exclamatory'],
        correctAnswer: 'c',
        word: 'Imperative',
        definition: 'An imperative sentence gives a command or makes a request.'
    },
    {
        question: ' Which type of sentence expresses strong emotions or exclamations?',
        choices: ['Declarative', 'Interrogative', 'Imperative', 'Exclamatory'],
        correctAnswer: 'd',
        word: 'Exclamatory',
        definition: 'An exclamatory sentence expresses strong emotions or excitement. Example: What a beautiful sunset!'
    }
]

export default questions;